MOHAMMED ABDULLAH KHAN

Mobile: 07466691680 Email: abdullahkhank@hotmail.com Southall,London,UB2, United Kingdom.

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Self-motivated and disciplined Deskside Support professional with 10 years' experience providing 2nd line support across hardware and software. Work well independently, or in a group setting providing all facets of computer support & administration such as troubleshooting, installations, and maintenance. In-depth knowledge and understanding of numerous software packages and operating systems IT \Project solutions. Has sound deployment projects support and IT know ledge ranging from day to day issues to tackling long -term projects.

CERTIFICATIONS:

CCNA Completed Diploma in CCNA from Zoom Technologies, India **MCSE** Microsoft Certified System Engineer.

EDUCATION PROFILE:

MCSE - Training completed with all labs (2010)

CCNA: Cisco Certified Network Associate - Training completed with all labs (2015)

CompTIA A+ Hardware & Networking

Bachelor's in commerce: Osmania University, India.

Skills Profile:

Hardware: IBM Servers, HP Blade, Desk Pro client PCs, IBM, Dell, HP and Sony laptops, HP Laser printers & HP scanners, Lenovo Server Laptops & Desktops, Surface Laptops

Operating Systems: Windows Server 2012/2008/03/00, Windows 2000/ XP/ Pro/ 7/ 8/ 8.1/10 & Apple MAC.

Server & Technologies: Active Directory Administration (Group policy, DNS, WINS) DHCP, TCP/IP, VOIP, LANDesk, Cisco VPN client, VMware & Hyper-V, LAN / WAN, VLANs & Firewalls.

Work Experience:

Deployment Engineer / Tech Bar IT Support / Desktop Support - SKY UK, London. (Dec 2017 – July 2019)

- Working on a Deployment project of Windows 10 & Office 365 (on Surface laptops) upgrading to all the users which is around (4000) around the UK.
- Working in a team of 6, providing 2nd Line desktop support/ Floor Support to over 4,000 users.
- Responding to customer requests for IT services (including incidents, queries, and service requests) in a timely, polite, and efficient fashion, adhering to the defined SLAs using (Service Now)
- Accountable for **PC & Mac** Hardware build, Deployment, Troubleshoot, Repairs and Support.
- Supporting remote users in accessing corporate resources & video conference system (Polycom)

- Accountable for administration and support of Office 365 (One Drive, Teams, OneNote, Skype for Business, MFA, etc).
- Resolving issue related to Windows 7 & Windows 10, Mac OS.
- Performing new and refurbished desktop, laptop and printer configurations and installations
- Working in conjunction with other IT teams and the business to ensure the successful resolution of any desktop issues.
- Backup & Restore of User Data Includes (Documents, Outlook, and User Profiles etc.)
- Bitlocker Encryption management for users and Mobile device support (IOS, Android) Setting up new users and accounts management.
- Managing Apple MAC computers using JAMF-Casper.
- Managing the new Starter process & leaver process

WIN10 Deployment & Floorwalk Engineer, BLOOMBERG, LONDON (July 2017 - Dec 2017)

- I am responsible for Imaging & Deployment of Windows 7 & 10 operating system & bespoke applications. Desk cabling, Cisco phone installation & docking station installation.
- Troubleshooting Network connectivity issues, Lan Cabling, Configuring and maintaining Network Printers.
- Co-ordinate disposal of assets, wiping data from laptops and desktops.
- User data backup & transfer to new Win10 device. Outlook & Printer configuration.
- Making Appointments e the users to migrate them to new OS and managing the timescales appropriately.
- Working in conjunction with other IT teams and the business to ensure the successful resolution of any desktop issues.

1st & 2nd Line Support – P&G LIMITED (Coty) Basingstoke, London, UK. (April 2017 – June 2017)

- I am responsible for PC Hardware build, Deployment of Windows 7 & Windows 10, Repairs and Support.
- · Configuring and maintaining Windows server 2008, User's management, Active Directory.
- Making Appointments with the users to migrate them to new OS and managing the timescales appropriately.
- Working in conjunction with other IT teams and the business to ensure the successful resolution of any desktop issues.
- Troubleshooting Network connectivity issues, Lan Cabling, Configuring and maintaining Network Printers.
- Co-ordinate disposal of assets, wiping data from laptops and desktops.
- Setting up new users and accounts management.
- Backup & Restore of User Data Includes (Documents, Outlook, etc.)
- Install and configure end user applications as required as a part of the upgrade process.
- Laptop and Desktop support to include: Setup, Configuration, Software Installations, Security Applications and upgrades, Troubleshooting and upgrading hardware.

IT SUPPORT & MOBILE ENGINEER - AMSYS LIMITED. London (Nov 2016 - MARCH 2017)

- Supporting and maintaining MS-Server / Desktops
- Setting up new users and accounts management.
- Configuring Emails and administering mobile devices (Blackberry, IPhone, IPad).
- Install and configure end user applications as required as a part of the upgrade process.
- Manage end user expectations throughout the upgrade. Assisting user to choose create correct resolutions for their applications.
- Laptop and Desktop support to include: Setup, Configuration, Software Installations, Security Applications and upgrades, Troubleshooting and upgrading hardware.

Repairing & upgrading, all Samsung smartphones & devices.

WINDOWS 7 DEPLOY MENT ENGINEER – Barclays Bank (MAY 2016 – OCT 2016)

- Building Dell Desktops/Laptop (OS Windows 7 & Office 2010/2013). Hardware and software.
- VIP's and Staff pre-deployment checks (Drive mappings, Archive PST, user data, hardware peripherals).
- Undertake pre-upgrade checks on all computers to be upgraded or refreshed including the capture and storage of the results of checks to local NAS drive.
- Configuring Emails and administering mobile devices (Blackberry, IPhone, IPad).
- Install and configure end user applications as required as a part of the upgrade process.
- Manage end user expectations throughout the upgrade. Assisting user to choose create correct resolutions for their applications.
- Collect and archive end user computer inventory reports and computer data extracts.
- Holding weekly internal Technical meetings on progress of Rollout and documenting to Liaise with Project manager.

SENIOR CUSTOMER ENGINEER- TELEPAC- PORTUGAL (Jan 2013- Nov 2015)

- Providing Ist/2nd line desktop support (BAU) for around 2000 users based mainly in their Hook head office.
- Deploying Windows 7 with all standard corporate applications on Lenovo Laptops and desktops through SCCM
 2012
- Data migration, providing user face to face support and solving any technical and data migration related issues.
- Installing printers, scanners and configuring VOIP phones. Remote desktop access to users though BOMGAR.
- Diagnose and upgrade hardware such as memory, video & graphic cards, hard disk & motherboard.
- Support and initial user setup for Symantec encryption (PGP) and Outlook 365.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Date of Birth : JUNE 1979
Nationality : EU National

Driving license : Yes

Languages : English, Portuguese, Hindi & Urdu.

HOBBIES/INTERESTS:

I love travel and have been lucky enough to travel most of the world, I have had the privilege to experience many cultures and many people from all walks of life.

PERSONAL STRENGTH:

- Multi language skill helps in communicating with various people and working effectively in team.
- Analysis and design of various requirements. Very good Logical Thinking ability.
- A high sense of adaptability, raising to the need of the hour and willing to work with dedication for an organization that rewards excellence and perfection.

REFERENCES: Personal and professional references furnished upon request.